Guide to the Stevenson family papers,1902-1909.
Stevenson family papers, 1902-1909
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stevenson family papers, 1902-1909.
356
Lewis G. Stevenson
.1 cubic ft.
Tax receipts, correspondence, rental agreements, receipted bills, financial statements, account book.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and business and legal documents concerning the management of 1700 acres of Vermillion and Newton County, Indiana farms owned by W. O. Davis and Helen D. Stevenson, managed by Lewis G. Stevenson and others.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lewis G. Stevenson was the son of Adlai Ewing Stevenson, vice-president of the United States during Cleveland's second administration; Helen Davis, wife of Lewis G. Stevenson, was the daughter of W. O. Davis, proprietor of the Pantagraph, Bloomington, Illinois.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Tax receipts, correspondence, rental agreements, receipted bills, financial statements, and an account book concerning the management of 1700 acres of Vermillion and Newton County, Indiana farms owned by W. O. Davis and Helen D. Stevenson, managed by Lewis G. Stevenson and others. Correspondence includes letters from tenants both to landlord and agent showing the problems of the tenant-landlord relationship; letters from Chicago commission merchants containing data on railroad rates, prices of grain and hogs on the Chicago market; letter and pamphlet from the Northern Iowa Land Co., including a list of farms for rent and rental rates; letter concerning assessment for construction of Lawler Ditch, and blueprint for its construction, in Newton County, Indiana.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Stevenson family.; Davis, W.O.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1835-1914.; Stevenson, Helen D.; Stevenson, Lewis G.; Lawler Ditch.; Northern Iowa Land Co.
Subjects:
Rent charges.; Agriculture--Accounting--Indiana.; Agriculture--Indiana--Vermillion County.; Agriculture--Indiana--Newton County.; Landlord and tenant--Indiana.; Agricultural markets--Indiana.; Farm management--Indiana.; Real property--Indiana.; Finance--Indiana.; Agricultural prices--Indiana.; Farm produce.
Places:
Indiana--Economic conditions.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Blueprints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Letters addressed to L.G. Stevenson and to Adlai E. Stevenson I (all letters addressed to L.G.S. except where indicated), 1907-1909
    - July 29, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Sept. 21, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Sept. 23, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 6, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 12, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 26, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 15, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 20, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 21, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 23, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 26, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Feb. 14, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 9, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 20, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 20, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Apr. 28, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Apr. 30, 1908 (Box 1)
    - May 18, 1908 (Box 1)
    - June 1, 1908 (Box 1)
    - June 20, 1908 (Box 1)
    - June 30, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 16, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Jan. 20, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Feb. 10, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 12, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 14, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 20, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 20, 1909 (Box 1)
    - May 17, 1909 (Box 1)
    - May 18, 1909 (Box 1)
    - July 29, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Sept. 22, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Nov. 4, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Apr. 21, 1909 (Addressed to Adlai E. Stevenson I) (Box 1)
  - Business letters (rough drafts, carbon copies, or outgoing mail returned with endorsement of receipt) from Lewis or from Lewis and his family jointly, 1907-1909
    - Dec. 20, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Dec. 26, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 6, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Feb. 27, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Mar. 29, 1909? (Box 1)
    - Apr. 6, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Apr. 10, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Undated letter on McLean County Coal Company letterhead (Box 1)
    - Draft of a farming agreement, Jan. 1908 (Box 1)